# Laura Kendl

Cell: (850) 450-1865 E-mail: lkendl@live.com

### Summary:

Six years of management, information system administration, and technical support experience holding positions as an Information Assurance Officer and Security Representative of a Special LAN Information System serving as a U.S. Navy Information System Technician.

## **Key Qualifications:**

Exceptional Work Ethic Organized Technical Support
Leadership Employee Training Self-Motivated
System Administrator Project Management Security Disciplined

### **Experience**:

Second Class Petty Officer Information Technology Specialist, USN Special LAN Information System Security Officer Commander Submarine Forces Pacific, Pearl Harbor Hawaii 04/2012-04/2018

- Annually conducted over 3,050 security scans on 85 workstations.
- Network administrator of two computer systems containing ~1,000 users and 85 workstations
- Well versed in account creation and maintenance through Active Directory while maintaining a database of over 500 users, resulting in 100% customer satisfaction
- Managed sensitive DOD system data daily with no data loss, compromise or leakage
- Interacted with and educated users on DOD network system best security practices
- Instrumental to the installation, accreditation, testing, and implementation of a prototype Special LAN system

# Deli Clerk Rosauers Supermarkets 01/2011-01/2012

- Provided excellent customer service daily
- Assisted customers in locating products, loading and unloading items
- Answered telephone for inquiries and accepting orders for home delivery
- Reviewed orders of customers and overseeing their preparation and serving
- Operated and cleaned deli equipment and maintained stock and serving area cleanliness
- Operated electric slicers, ovens, dishwasher, knives, oil-filtering machine, etc.

# Library Page Shiawassee District Library 11/2005-03/2010

- Provided caring and efficient services to various demographics, from children to those with special needs
- Maintained and organized over 3,000 media, to include books, CDs, DVDs and microfilms

## **Certifications:**

Certified CompTIA Security+	(2015)
Certified CompTIA A+	(2012)

#### Education:

B.A. Web Development, Bellevue University	(Expected 2023)
Automated Digital Network System (ADNS)	(2015)
Navy Enlisted Classifications 2379 (Transmission System Technician)	(2013)
Navy Enlisted Classifications 2790 (Information Systems Technician)	(2012)
Navy Course: Information Systems Technician Class "A"	(2012)
21 Credits, Grand Valley State University	(2010)
High School Diploma, Owosso High School	(2010)

### **Additional Skills:**

- Understanding of audit and compliance processes
- Strong experience with DOD network security concepts
- Passion for cybersecurity concepts, ideas, and network defense
- Self-driven and motivated with the ability to work independently of others
- Attention to detail, ensuring that effective controls are developed and maintained to ensure the integrity of the organization
- Operates and troubleshoots software and hardware, local area networks (LANs) and Microsoft Windows server
- Knowledge of Cisco Network Fundamentals, Information Technology Essentials and Server Administration
- Knowledge of network addressing and protocols; command-line interfacing in Linux; and maintaining and configuring CISCO routers
- Performs core and specialty functions of communications operations, message processing, and network administration and security
- Knowledge of configuring external peripherals, workstations network connectivity, and operating system software

### Awards:

Navy and Marine Corps Achievement Medal (NAM) from COMSUBPAC	(2018)
Good Conduct Award	(2018)
Navy and Marine Corps Achievement Medal (NAM) from POW/MIA	(2015)